Hi, my name is David Brown, and this is a reading writing class.
مرحباً، اسمي ديفيد براون، وهذا درسٌ في القراءة والكتابة.
Hello, welcome. How are you?
أهلاً، مرحباً بك. كيف حالُكَ؟
Hi, nice to meet you.
أهلاً، سررتُ بلقائك.
Nice to meet you too. My name is David. What's your name?
وأنا أيضاً سررتُ بلقائك. اسمي ديفيد. ما اسمُكَ؟
My name is Francesco. Pleasure to meet you, David.
اسمي فرانشيسكو. من دواعي سروري أن ألتقي بك يا ديفيد.
Nice to meet you, Francesco. Welcome.
سررتُ بلقائك يا فرانشيسكو. أهلاً بك.
I see that you selected a lesson about Walt Whitman and his famous poem,
أرى أنك اخترت درساً عن والت ويتمان وقصيدته الشهيرة،
Oh, captain, my captain, a reading and writing class. Is that right?
"أوه، أيها القبطان، يا قبطاني!"، وهو درسٌ في القراءة والكتابة. هل هذا صحيح؟
Yes, that is correct.
نعم، هذا صحيح.
Okay, great.
حسناً، عظيم.
So I'll tell you a little bit about Abraham Lincoln.
إذاً، سأحدثك قليلاً عن أبراهام لينكولن.
You've probably heard of honest Abe before he was the 16th US president.
ربما سمعت عن "آيب النزيه" من قبل، لقد كان الرئيس السادس عشر للولايات المتحدة.
He was assassinated in 1865.
لقد اغتيل عام 1865.
You might compare him to another famous leader. Do you know who this guy is?
قد تقارنه بزعيم شهير آخر. هل تعرف من هذا الرجل؟
Yes, Francisco Morazán.
نعم، فرانشيسكو مورازان.
Francisco Morazán. Okay, so they're not the same, but they are very popular presidents, right?
فرانشيسكو مورازان. حسناً، إنهما مختلفان، لكنهما رئيسان يتمتعان بشعبية كبيرة، أليس كذلك؟
Correct. Yes.
صحيح. نعم.
So this question for us is what makes a good leader?
إذاً السؤال المطروح علينا هو: ما الذي يجعل القائد جيداً؟
Take a minute to think about it, and then you can share with me and talk about this.
خذ دقيقة للتفكير في الأمر، ثم يمكنك أن تشاركني رأيك ونتحدث عن هذا.
What makes a good leader in your opinion?
ما الذي يجعل القائد جيداً في رأيك؟
Okay.
حسناً.
Do you want me to write it down or can I just start?
هل تريدني أن أكتبه أم يمكنني أن أبدأ مباشرة؟
Yeah, you can.
نعم، يمكنك ذلك.
I think it's not only someone that inspires, but also knows when to take action.
أعتقد أنه ليس فقط شخصٌ يُلهم، بل يعرف أيضاً متى يتخذ إجراءً.
Okay.
حسناً.
Alright, agreed. Somebody with initiative, right?
حسناً، أتفق معك. شخص لديه روح المبادرة، صحيح؟
Yes, absolutely.
نعم، بالتأكيد.
I think both of these leaders were leaders who inspired others and took a great initiative.
أعتقد أن كلا هذين القائدين كانا قائدين ألهما الآخرين واتخذا مبادرة عظيمة.
I would agree.
أتفق مع ذلك.
Both of them were involved with some great liberal reforms as well.
كلاهما شارك في بعض الإصلاحات الليبرالية الكبرى أيضاً.
Alright, so we have a list of things that can help us to improve our English in particular reading and writing and speaking too since we'll be having a conversation throughout the entire lesson.
حسناً، إذاً لدينا قائمة بأشياء يمكن أن تساعدنا على تحسين لغتنا الإنجليزية، وخاصة في القراءة والكتابة وكذلك المحادثة، حيث سنجري محادثة طوال الدرس بأكمله.
These are our class objectives.
هذه هي أهداف درسنا.
Can you read the class objectives starting with this one here?
هل يمكنك أن تقرأ أهداف الدرس بدءاً من هذا الهدف هنا؟
Yes, identify and explain the historical context of O-Captain, My Captain.
نعم، تحديد وشرح السياق التاريخي لقصيدة "أوه، أيها القبطان، يا قبطاني!".
Define key vocabulary.
تعريف المفردات الرئيسية.
For example,
على سبيل المثال،
?legy,
مرثية،
keel, rack,
عارضة السفينة، محنة،
or is it
أم أنها
elegy.
مرثية.
And identify and extend it metaphor within the poem.
وتحديد الاستعارة الممتدة في القصيدة.
Analyze the extended metaphor, explaining what the captain, ship, fearful trip and prize represent.
تحليل الاستعارة الممتدة، وشرح ما يمثله القبطان، والسفينة، والرحلة المخيفة، والجائزة.
Discuss the tone of the poem as it relates to grief and admiration.
مناقشة نبرة القصيدة من حيث صلتها بالحزن والإعجاب.
And express understanding of the poem through discussion and written responses.
والتعبير عن فهم القصيدة من خلال المناقشة والإجابات المكتوبة.
Okay.
حسناً.
Oh, and connect the poem's themes of loss, leadership, and national strategy to broader concepts of freedom.
أوه، وربط موضوعات القصيدة عن الفقدان، والقيادة، والاستراتيجية الوطنية بمفاهيم أوسع للحرية.
Is it a freedom?
هل هي حرية؟
Like freedom.
مثل الحرية.
Yeah.
نعم.
Oh, like freedom.
آه، مثل الحرية.
Alright, so we have a lot that we can do.
حسناً، إذاً لدينا الكثير لنقوم به.
We might not have time to do all of this, but certainly there is a lot to digest about this poem.
قد لا يكون لدينا وقت للقيام بكل هذا، ولكن بالتأكيد هناك الكثير لنتعمق فيه بخصوص هذه القصيدة.
And well, well, Whitman and historical context here.
وبالطبع، والت ويتمان والسياق التاريخي هنا.
The vocabulary can be a little bit antiquated because it's, it was written in 1865 right after the assassination of Abraham Lincoln.
يمكن أن تكون المفردات قديمة نوعاً ما لأنها كُتبت عام 1865 مباشرة بعد اغتيال أبراهام لينكولن.
So I just want you to keep that in mind as we read this.
لذا أريدك فقط أن تضع ذلك في اعتبارك ونحن نقرأ هذا.
There's a context to this poem.
لهذه القصيدة سياق.
And maybe it's talking about something a little deeper.
وربما تتحدث عن شيء أعمق قليلاً.
So when we say extended metaphor, you know, a metaphor is when A is B.
فعندما نقول استعارة ممتدة، كما تعلم، الاستعارة هي عندما يكون "أ" هو "ب".
But an extended metaphor is when maybe a whole paragraph or text is standing for something.
لكن الاستعارة الممتدة هي عندما تكون فقرة كاملة أو نص كامل يرمز إلى شيء ما.
Okay.
حسناً.
So some historical context here.
إذاً، إليك بعض السياق التاريخي.
But first here, what do you know about the American Civil War or Abraham Lincoln?
ولكن أولاً هنا، ماذا تعرف عن الحرب الأهلية الأمريكية أو أبراهام لينكولن؟
Oh, I know, I know the nickname honest Abe.
أوه، أعرف، أعرف لقب "آيب النزيه".
(The) American Civil War was specifically regarding slavery.
الحرب الأهلية الأمريكية كانت تتعلق تحديداً بالعبودية.
If I'm not mistaken, correct?
إن لم أكن مخطئاً، صحيح؟
Yes.
نعم.
North and the South.
الشمال والجنوب.
And then Abraham Lincoln.
ثم أبراهام لينكولن.
Well, you said the 16th president, but I think there's something.
حسناً، لقد قلت الرئيس السادس عشر، لكن أعتقد أن هناك شيئاً ما.
I think there was a very important decision he took and I can't quite remember it.
أعتقد أنه اتخذ قراراً مهماً جداً ولا أتذكره تماماً.
Something that he's really known about.
شيء يُعرف به حقاً.
The emancipation proclamation.
إعلان تحرير العبيد.
Yeah.
نعم.
All right.
حسناً.
Excellent.
ممتاز.
So you know some about the American Civil War in the context of this poem.
إذاً أنت تعرف بعض الشيء عن الحرب الأهلية الأمريكية في سياق هذه القصيدة.
How important this was the Civil War in the United States.
كم كانت هذه الحرب الأهلية مهمة في الولايات المتحدة.
Didn't just affect the United States had a cascade effect to other countries.
لم تؤثر فقط على الولايات المتحدة، بل كان لها تأثير متتالٍ على دول أخرى.
And really changed a lot of attitudes.
وغيرت الكثير من المواقف حقاً.
And it wasn't over at the end of the Civil War.
ولم ينتهِ الأمر بنهاية الحرب الأهلية.
And it's still not over.
وما زال الأمر لم ينتهِ.
Really, we still fight with inequality.
حقاً، ما زلنا نكافح ضد عدم المساواة.
We still fight with issues related to slavery around the world.
ما زلنا نكافح القضايا المتعلقة بالعبودية حول العالم.
And this question about what it really means to be free.
وهذا السؤال حول ماذا يعني حقاً أن تكون حراً.
And it's still an uphill battle.
وما زالت معركة شاقة.
So we what Whitman wrote, oh, captain, my captain in 1865 shortly after two major events here.
لذلك كتب والت ويتمان "أوه، أيها القبطان، يا قبطاني!" عام 1865 بعد وقت قصير من حدثين رئيسيين هنا.
Can you read this part for us?
هل يمكنك أن تقرأ لنا هذا الجزء؟
Of course, the end of the Civil War, which lasted from 1861 to 1865.
بالطبع، نهاية الحرب الأهلية، التي استمرت من 1861 إلى 1865.
A rural conflict that divided the nation.
صراع وحشي قسّم الأمة.
And the assassination of President Abraham Abraham Lincoln in April 1865 just days after the Confederates surrender.
واغتيال الرئيس أبراهام لينكولن في أبريل 1865 بعد أيام قليلة فقط من استسلام الكونفدراليين.
Lincoln was seen by many as the captain who had steered the nation.
اعتبر الكثيرون لينكولن القبطان الذي وجه دفة الأمة.
the ship... through the fearful trip of the war.
السفينة... عبر رحلة الحرب المخيفة.
So we see an example of a metaphor already the nation as the ship he steered it he was the captain.
إذاً نرى بالفعل مثالاً على الاستعارة: الأمة كسفينة، وهو من قادها، لقد كان القبطان.
in this poem that we're going to read.
في هذه القصيدة التي سنقرأها.
So that we have another colored picture of Abraham Lincoln.
وهنا لدينا صورة ملونة أخرى لأبراهام لينكولن.
I just think it's cool that they can put color to old pictures now.
أعتقد أنه من الرائع أنهم يستطيعون الآن تلوين الصور القديمة.
And it makes it look real.
ويجعلها تبدو حقيقية.
And a scene from something that you would have seen in the newspaper.
ومشهد مما كنتم سترونه في الصحف.
So Abraham Lincoln was in a theater when he was shot and assassinated.
إذاً، كان أبراهام لينكولن في مسرح عندما أُطلق عليه النار واغتيل.
All right.
حسناً.
So here we have some terms that we need to know.
إذاً هنا لدينا بعض المصطلحات التي نحتاج إلى معرفتها.
And you might hesitate with some of these vocabulary words.
وقد تتردد في بعض هذه المفردات.
They're a little difficult.
إنها صعبة بعض الشيء.
So we have lyric, elegy, metaphor and extended metaphor.
لدينا الشعر الغنائي، المرثية، الاستعارة، والاستعارة الممتدة.
Lyric poetry is poetry that expresses personal emotions or feelings.
الشعر الغنائي هو شعر يعبر عن عواطف أو مشاعر شخصية.
It's typically spoken in the first person.
وعادةً ما يُروى بضمير المتكلم.
So the poem that we're about to read is lyric poetry.
فالقصيدة التي نحن على وشك قراءتها هي شعر غنائي.
And this one, remember the pronunciation, elegy, could you read this for us?
وهذه، تذكر النطق، مرثية، هل يمكنك أن تقرأ لنا هذا؟
Yes.
نعم.
A poem of serious reflection, typically a lament for the dead.
قصيدة تأمل جاد، وعادة ما تكون رثاءً للموتى.
Oh, captain, my captain is an elegy for Abraham Lincoln.
"أوه، أيها القبطان، يا قبطاني!" هي مرثية لأبراهام لينكولن.
All right.
حسناً.
So we're talking about someone a captain who was killed.
إذاً نحن نتحدث عن شخص ما، قبطان قُتل.
And so the poem is really deep.
وبالتالي فالقصيدة عميقة حقاً.
And it's a little dark in that sense.
وقاتمة بعض الشيء بهذا المعنى.
You have to imagine the feeling at the end of a war.
عليك أن تتخيل الشعور في نهاية الحرب.
The feeling at the end of the war is one of relief.
الشعور في نهاية الحرب هو شعور بالارتياح.
you could imagine, but also great sadness.
كما يمكنك أن تتخيل، ولكن أيضاً حزن عميق.
You can't bring back the lives that were lost.
لا يمكنك استعادة الأرواح التي فُقدت.
You can't undo what was done.
لا يمكنك إلغاء ما حدث.
What was done was done.
ما حدث قد حدث.
We have a metaphor, a figure of speech in which a word or phrase is applied.
لدينا الاستعارة، وهي صورة بلاغية يُطبق فيها كلمة أو عبارة.
So when one thing is another, and then this extension of that, the extended metaphor.
فعندما يكون شيء ما شيئاً آخر، ثم هذا امتداد لذلك، الاستعارة الممتدة.
Could you read this one for us?
هل يمكنك أن تقرأ لنا هذا؟
Yes.
نعم.
A metaphor that is developed over several lines of writing or even throughout an entire work.
استعارة تتطور عبر عدة أسطر من الكتابة أو حتى عبر عمل كامل.
Great.
ممتاز.
So here's the first reading.
إذاً هذه هي القراءة الأولى.
I'll read this first one for you.
سأقرأ لك هذا الجزء الأول.
I want you to listen to the way that this sounds.
أريدك أن تستمع إلى كيف يبدو هذا في النطق.
While follow eyes and steady keel.
بينما تتبع العيون اليقظة والعارضة الثابتة.
The vessel grim and daring.
السفينة الصارمة والجريئة.
But oh, heart, heart, heart.
ولكن آه، يا قلبي، يا قلبي، يا قلبي!
Oh, the bleeding drops of red.
آه، قطرات الدم الحمراء النازفة!
Where on the deck, my captain lies, fallen cold and dead.
حيث على السطح، يرقد قبطاني، سقط بارداً وميتاً.
So we have this image of a ship with a keel.
إذاً لدينا هذه الصورة لسفينة ذات عارضة.
So certain part of the ship, right?
إذاً جزء معين من السفينة، صحيح؟
The vessel grim and daring.
السفينة الصارمة والجريئة.
You see this dark ship entering.
ترى هذه السفينة المظلمة تدخل.